- Hi,guys. - Hey,Phoebe.
- 各位 - 菲比
- How did it go? - Not so good.
- 你的约会怎么样? - 不是很好
He walked me home and said, "Let's do this again."
他送我到地铁然后跟我说 我们应该再来一次
He said,"Let's do this again." That's good,right?
他说要再来一次? 那不是很好吗?
Translated,"Let's do this again" means,"You'll never see me naked."
不，他说我们应该再来一次 意思是说你将无法再见到裸体的我
Since when?
什么时候这样子的？
Since always. It's,like,dating language.
一直都是这样的啊. 就像是…约会用语
Like,"It's not you" means,"It is you."
比如,“问题不是出在你”代表“就是你”
"You're nice" means,"I'll be dating alcoholics..
“你真好”意思是说我要和皮革族的酒徒约会…
and complaining about them to you."
然后向你抱怨
"We should see other people" means:
“我们该试试别人”代表
"Ha-ha,I already am!"
“我已和别人约会了”
Everybody knows this?
大家都懂?
Cushions the blow.
对，善意的谎言
Like your parents putting the dog to sleep..
没错，就像父母使小孩的狗安乐死时
and saying it went to a farm.
他们会说它跑到别人家农场去住了
That's funny. Because our parents actually did..
真有意思,不过我爸妈是真的…
send our dog off to live on a farm.
把我们的狗送给别人养了
Ross?
罗斯？
Hello! The Milner's farm in Connecticut?
米纳他们在康乃迪克州的农场
The Milners had this unbelievable farm.
米纳他们家的农场好棒
They had horses and rabbits to chase.
有马还有可供追逐的兔子…
And it was..
Oh,my God! Chi-Chi!
噢,芝芝
The One With the Thumb
六人行 第1季 第03集 飞来横财
-=BT之家DRM小组 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 荣誉出品 河马根据网络字幕微调制作
How does it feel knowing you're about to die?
知道自己不久人世有何感受?
Warden,in five minutes my pain will be over.
华顿，我的痛苦将在五分钟内消除
But you'll live with the knowledge that you sent an honest man to die.
但你得承受埋葬一个老实人的痛苦
That was really good!
表演得真好是吗？
Thanks. Let's keep going.
谢了，咱们继续吧
So,what do you want from me,Dimon? Huh?
好，你要我怎么做，迪默?
I just wanna go back to my cell, because in my cell I can smoke.
我只想回到我的牢房内 因为这样我才可以抽烟
Smoke away!
你就在这里抽吧
I think this is why Dimon smokes in his cell alone.
我想这就是迪默自己一个在牢房里抽烟的原因
- What? - Relax your hand.
- 什么 - 手放轻松
Let your wrist go.
手腕自然点
Not so much!
别太过火!
All right. Now take a puff.
好的，现在吐口烟
Right.
就是这样
- Give it to me. - I'm not giving you a cigarette.
- 给我来 - 不，我不能给你烟
It's fine. Do you want to get this part or not? Here.
无所谓的，你到底想不想演这个角色?来
Now,don't think of it as a cigarette.
看着，别把它当成香烟
Think of it as the thing that has been missing from your hand.
把它当成是你想念多时的东西
When you hold it, you feel right.
夹着它你感到自在
You feel complete.
让你感到满足
- You miss it? - No,not so much.
- 你很想它? - 没那么严重
All right. Now we smoke.
好吧，抽烟
Oh,my God!
噢,爽呀!
- Give me that! - No. You've got options.
- 把它给我 - 不，你有几种选择
You can smoke like this:
你可以像这样抽烟
- Chandler - Or hold it in your mouth.
- 钱德 - 或者只是把它叼在嘴里
Give me the cigarette!
把烟给我
- You try. - Thank you.
- 你来试试. - 谢谢
Okay,how's this?
感觉怎么样？
Okay,that's not bad.
还不坏
All right,when you're finished, it's cool if you flick it.
好的，当你结束的时候, 弹掉它会显得很酷
All right,you keep practicing..
就这样，不断练习
and I'll go put out the sofa.
我去扑灭着火的沙发
I thought it was foot size.
我认为一个人脚的大小
No. It's the distance from the tip of a guy's thumb..
不，是和他拇指尖到食指尖…
to the tip of his index finger.
的距离相同的
That's ridiculous.
这太荒谬了
Can I use either thumb?
随便哪个姆指都行?
I'd rather go with the foot theory.
我宁可和脚长理论相伴
All right. Don't tell me.
别告诉我…
Decaf cappuccino for Joey.
无咖啡因卡布其诺，是乔依的
Coffee,black.
纯咖啡
Latte.
拿铁
And an iced tea.
和冰茶
- I'm getting good at this. - Excellent!
- 我进步神速 - 不错
Good for me!
我真行
- You okay,Phoebe? - It's not worth
- 菲此，你没事吧 - 我还好
It's my bank.
我的银行
- What did they do? - It's nothing
他们对你怎么了?
I get my mail and open their monthly "statement."
我看我的信件时 看见他们的每月通知
Easy!
别激动
And there's $500 extra in my account.
我的户头多了五百元
Satan's minions at work again!
撒旦的奴才又开始活跃了
Now I have to go deal with them
没错，因为我得到银行找他们处理
- What are you talking about? Keep it! - It's not mine.
- 别傻了，留着自己用吧 - 这些钱不是我的
If I kept it,I'd be stealing.
我留下来就如同偷窃
But if you spent it, it would be like shopping.
如果你拿来花就如同购物
Say I bought a great pair of shoes.
好吧，就比方说我买了一双很棒的鞋
Know what I'd hear with every step? "Not mine. Not mine. Not mine."
你们知道我每踏出一步都会听到什么吗? “不是我的…不是我的…不是我的…”
Even if I was happy and skipping,I'd hear:
即使我再快乐再雀跃都会听到
"Not-not mine. Not-not mine."
“不是我的…不是我的…”
We're with you. We got it.
知道你的意思了
I'd never be able to enjoy it. It'd be this giant karmic debt.
我无法享受非份之财的乐趣 这就像是业报一样
Chandler,what are you doing?
钱德，你在干什么?
What are you doing?
你在干什么?
Oh,gross!
噢,真恶劣!
- What is this? - I'm smoking!
- 这是什么 - 我在抽烟…
You've been so good for three years!
你这三年来一直表现良好
And this is my reward.
这是我的奖励
Think about what you went through when you quit.
等等，想想你戒烟后是怎么活过来的
Forget about you. Think about what we went through!
就算忘了你自己,至少想想我们是怎么过来的
So this time I won't quit.
所以这一次我不再戒了
- Put it out! - I'm putting it out!
- 熄掉… - 好吧，我熄掉就是
Oh,no!
噢,不!
I can't drink this now.
拜托，我现在喝不了它了
I'm gonna go. I've got a date.
我要去换衣服了,我有个约会
With Alan again? How's it going?
又是亚伦?进展得如何?
It's going pretty good. It's nice and we're having fun.
进展的还不错.我们在一起很开心
When do we get to meet him?
我们何时能见到他?
Let's see,it's Monday..
今天是星期一…
- Never. - Come on!
- 永远别想… - 不要这样嘛
Not after what happened with Steve.
不,不要再来像史提夫那次的事…
What do you mean? We love Steve. Steve was sexy!
你在说什么?我们都爱史提夫 史提夫很性感
Sorry.
抱歉
I don't know how I feel yet. Let me figure it out.
我连自己对他有何感觉都还不知道 给我一点时间想清楚
Then can we meet him?
这么说我们可以见他罗?
No.
不行
Sorry.
抱歉
Joey. Let it go.
乔伊.放过它吧
Why should they meet him?
我为何要让他们见他?
I bring a guy home and they're like..
我带他回去後，他们就像
coyotes picking off the weak members of the herd.
就像郊狼一样找弱者下手
Listen,as someone who's seen more than her share of bad beef..
听着，不愉快的场面我见多了
I'll tell you, that is not such a terrible thing.
告诉你这并不是一件坏事
Your friends are just looking after you.
你的朋友他们只是关心你
I wish that once I'd date a guy they liked.
我只希望带一个 他们真正喜欢的男人回家
You realize the odds of that happening are slimmer..
你知道的，他的机会会更渺茫的…
- if they never get to meet the guy. - I know.
- 如果他们根本就没见过这小伙 - 这个我知道
- Can't I whimper a little bit? - Whimper.
- 能让我小声的哭一下吗？ - 哭
Okay,I'm done.
不要这样子
Let it go,Ross.
罗斯,让它去吧!
You didn't know Chi-Chi.
你又不了解芝芝
- Do you all promise? - We promise.
- 你们都保证? - 对，我们保证
We'll be good.
我们会很乖的
Chandler,do you promise to be good?
钱德，你保证会很乖?
You can come in,but your filter-tip buddy stays outside!
你可以进来了,但是 你的烟屁股朋友得呆在外面
"Dear Ms. Buffay. Thank you for calling.
亲爱的巴菲小姐 谢谢你提醒我们的错误
We've credited you $500. We're sorry for the inconvenience..
我们已将五百元存入你的户头 造成不便之处请多包涵
and hope you'll accept this football phone..
请接受此足球电话…
as our gift." Do you believe it?
做为礼物 你们相信吗？
Now I have $ 1000 and a football phone.
现在我多了一千元和一个足球电话
What bank is this?
这是哪家银行?
Okay,it's him.
他来了
- Who is it? - Alan.
- 这位是谁啊？ - 亚伦
Chandler! He's here!
钱德，他来了
Do I look okay?
我看起来怎么样？
One more button.
最好再扣上一颗扣子
Closed! How about closed?
-我是说扣上！扣上怎么样？
- I didn't know. - Yeah.
- 我不太清楚 - 好吧
Please be good.
拜托，别乱来
Remember how much you all like me?
记得你们有多么爱我
Alan,this is everybody. Everybody,this is Alan.
亚伦，这是大家 各位，他是亚伦
I've heard so much about all you guys.
我对各位已如雷灌耳
I'll call you tomorrow. Thanks.
谢谢，我明天再打电话给你
Let's let the Alan-bashing begin.
开始攻击亚伦吧
Who's gonna take the first shot?
谁先开始?
Come on!
来呀
I'll go.
我来
Let's start with how he kept picking
我们就从他不停剔牙开始
I'm sorry,I can't do this. We loved him.
抱歉,我办不到.我们爱他
We loved him!
我们爱他
Wait! We're talking about someone I'm going out with?
等等，我们谈的是我约会的对象吗?
That pimento trick!
那个辣椒的小把戏
I'll never look at an olive the same way again.
我绝不会再这样看橄榄了
And did you notice?
你们都有注意到?
Know what was great? His smile was crooked.
知道他什么最棒吗? 他的微笑有点邪邪的
- Yes! Like the man in the shoe! - What shoe?
对，就像是鞋里的男人 - 什么鞋?
From the rhyme.
童谣里的
There was a man With a crooked smile
有个驼背的人有着扭曲的微笑
Who lived in a shoe For a while
他住在鞋子里，有一阵子
So I think Alan..
我想亚伦…
is the yardstick by which future boyfriends will be measured.
将成为日后男友被丈量的标准
Future boyfriends?
什么日后男友?
- I think this could be "it." - Really?
- 不，我想他就是了 - 真的呀?
I'd marry him for his David Hasselhoff impression alone.
光凭他学海滩游侠的样子 我就想嫁给他了
You know I'll be doing that at parties.
你知道嘛，我也要在派对上这么做
- Know what I like most? - What?
- 知道我最喜欢他哪一点? - 哪一点？
The way he makes me feel about myself.
他改变我看待自己的方式
How was the game?
比赛如何?
Well..
怎么说呢
We won!
我们赢啦
Fantastic! Question. How is that possible?
神奇!提问：这怎么可能呢？
- Alan. - He was unbelievable!
- 亚伦 - 他真是太不可思议了
Like the cartoon where Bugs Bunny plays every position.
他就像兔宝宝一样守每个位置
It was first base,Alan. Second base,Alan..
但我们有一垒手亚伦、二垒手亚伦…
It was like he made us into a team.
他使我们形成一个团队
We sure showed those Hasidic jewelers a thing or two about softball.
对，我们让对手见识到什么叫垒球
Can I ask a question?
能问你们一个问题吗?
Do you think Alan is sometimes..
你是否曾感觉亚伦有时…
What?
有时怎样?
I don't know. A little too "Alan"?
我说不上来，太亚伦了
Oh,no. Not possible. You can never be too "Alan."
不，不可能 你不可能太过於“亚伦”
It's his innate "Alan-ness" that we adore.
没错我们欣赏的是亚伦的内在
I,personally,could have a gallon of Alan.
我…一个人可以喝下一加仑的亚伦
- Hey,Lizzy. - Hey,weird girl.
- 嘿,露西 - 嘿,古怪女孩
- I brought alphabet soup. - Pick out the vowels?
- 我带字母汤来给你 - 你挑出有元音了吗?
I left in the Y's. Because,"sometimes Y."
但我把“Y”留下来了 因为有时你会用的上,“Why”(音同Y)
- And something else. - Saltines?
- 我还带了其他东西给你 - 咸饼干吗?
No,$1000 and a football phone.
但愿你喜欢一千元和足球电话
What?
什么?
Oh,my God!
天啊
- There's really money in here. - I know.
- 这里真的有钱 - 这我知道
What are you doing?
你在干什么?
I want you to have it. I don't want it.
我要给你，我不想要
- I have to give you something. - No,you don't
- 不，我得拿东西给你 - 不用了
- Do you want my tinfoil hat? - No,you need that.
- 你要我的锡箔纸帽帽吗? - 不要，因为你需要
- It's okay. Thanks. - Let me do something.
- 不用了，谢谢 - 求你,让我表示我的谢意
I'll tell you what. Buy me a soda and we're even. Okay?
这样吧,你请我喝汽水就扯平了
- Okay. - Okay.
- 好吧 - 好吧
Keep the change.
不用找了
Thanks,Lizzy.
谢谢你，莉兹
Want a pretzel?
你真的不要椒盐卷饼?
- No,I'm fine. Thanks. - See you.
- 不,不用了 - 再见
A thumb?
一个拇指？
I know. There it was, just floating..
我知道.我打开时它就浮在里面
like this tiny little hitchhiker.
像个搭便车的
Maybe it's a contest. Like "collect all five."
或者这是一场竞赛,比如集满五个有奖?
- Does anyone wanna see? - No,thanks!
- 你们想看看吗? - 不用了，谢谢
Don't do that. Come on!
别那样，拜托
It's worse than the thumb.
这比姆指还糟糕
- This is so unfair. - Why is it unfair?
- 这不公平 - 为何不公平?
So I have a flaw! Big deal!
我有缺点行吗?了不起
Joey's knuckle-cracking isn't annoying?
乔依常扳指关节就不惹人厌?
Ross,over-pronouncing every word.
罗斯把每个音发得太清楚
Monica,who snorts when she laughs. I mean,what the hell is that thing?
摩妮卡大笑时的鼻音 搞什么嘛
I accept those flaws. Why can't you accept me for this?
我接受大家所有的缺点 为何大家就不肯接受我的呢?
Does the knuckle-cracking bother everybody,or just him?
扳指关节会惹人厌吗?还是只是他比较烦
I could live without it.
没有它我也能活的下去
Is it a little annoying? Or is it like when Phoebe chews her hair?
我觉得有点点烦? 感觉就和看到菲此咬她的头发时一样?
Don't listen to him. I think it's endearing.
菲此，别介意 我觉得那样很可爱
Oh,you do,do you?
真的?是吗?
There's nothing wrong with speaking correctly.
咬字清晰又不犯法
Indeed there isn't.
没错
I should get back to work.
我该回去工作了
Otherwise someone might get what they ordered.
否则有人就会拿错他们点的东西
The hair comes out and the gloves come off.
头发冒了出来，手套滑落下来 (全都发泄出来了)
Ever go out with a guy your friends really like?
你曾和一个你朋友都喜欢的男人约会吗?
No.
没有
I'm going out with a guy my friends really like.
我在和一个我朋友都喜欢的男人约会
Are we talking about the coyotes here?
我们在谈郊狼吗?
All right! A cow got through.
一头牛居然全身而退
Can you believe it?
你能相信吗?
It's just,you know what?
就像是，你知道吗…
I just don't feel the "thing."
我毫无感觉
They feel the thing. I don't feel it.
而他们却有感觉.我毫无感觉
Honey,you should always feel the thing.
你应该要有感觉
If that's how you feel about the guy, dump him.
如果对他没感觉,就把他甩了
- It's gonna be really hard. - He'll get over it.
- 我知道，但很难 - 没错，但他是大人了,他会熬过去的
No,he'll be fine. It's the other five I'm worried about.
不，他没事.我担心的是其他五人
- Don't you respect your body? - Don't you see what you're doing?
- 难道你不尊重你的身体吗? - 你难道不明白自己自己在做什么吗?
I've had it with your cancer, emphysema and heart disease.
还有你们的癌症肺气肿和心脏病
The bottom line is,smoking is cool, and you know it.
至少抽烟很酷,这点你们也很清楚
Alan wants to speak to you.
钱德，亚伦找你
Really? He does?
真的,他找我?
Hey,buddy! What's up?
老兄，什么事?
She told you about that,huh?
她告诉你了?
Well,yeah. I have one now and then. Well,yeah,now.
对，我偶尔会犯烟瘾 对，现在
It's not that
没那么糟
Well,that's true.
这倒是真的
Gee,you know,no one's ever put it like that before.
天啊，没人这么说过
Well,okay. Thanks.
好的，谢谢
God,he's good.
天啊，他真神
- If only he were a woman. - Yeah.
- 如果他是个女人,那该有多好 - 是的啊
Lamb Chop!
小羊排!
How old is that sock?
那袜子到底有多旧了?
If I had a sock on my hand for 30 years,it'd be talking too.
如果我手上戴着袜子三十年 它也会开始说话
I think it's time to change somebody's nicotine patch.
有人该换尼古丁贴片了
- Where's Joey? - Joey ate my last stick of gum..
- 乔依在哪儿? - 乔依吃了我的最後一片口香糖
so I killed him.
所以我就把他杀了
Do you think that was wrong?
你认为这样不对吗?
- I think he's across the hall. - Thanks.
- 我想他在对面 - 谢谢
There you go.
好啦
I'm alive with pleasure now.
我又重拾快乐的生活
Phoebe,do you want the rest of that Pop-Tart?
菲此，你还想吃那个吗?
Does anyone want the rest of this Pop-Tart?
谁想吃剩下的?
Hey,I might.
我要
I'm sorry.
抱歉
The soda people gave me $7000 for the thumb.
汽水公司那些笨蛋 给我七千元当姆指的补偿金
And on my way over here I stepped in gum.
天啊，七千元别闹了 我回家路上又踩到口香糖
What is up with the universe?
这世界到底怎么了?
- What's going on? - It's just nice when we're together.
- 怎么啦？ - 只是觉得大夥儿在一起很温馨
It's nicer when everyone gets to wear underwear.
如果大家都有穿内裤会更好
Please,guys,we have to talk.
大家，我有话要说
Wait! I'm getting a deja vu.
等等，我有似曾相识的感觉
No,I'm not.
不,好像没有
- We have to talk. - There it is!
- 好吧,我们需要谈谈. - 瞧,来了
Okay,it's about Alan.
是有关亚伦的事
Speaking of which,tell him we're on for the Renaissance Fair.
关于什么，告诉他文艺复兴已经开始了
Before you get into that, there's something you should know.
在此之前，有件事应该让你们知道
There's really no easy way to say this.
真的很难启齿
I've decided to break up with Alan.
我决定和亚伦分手
Is there somebody else?
有第三者?
No,it's just..
没有
you know,things change. People change.
只是世事难料，人都会变
We didn't change.
我们没变
So that's it? It's over?
就这样?结束了?
Just like that?
就这样结束了
You let your guard down. You start to care about someone,and..
放下防御，真心对待一个人…
- I can go on pretending - Okay!
- 我可以继续伪装… - 可以啊
No.
不
That wouldn't be fair to me,Alan, or to you.
这样对我不公平,对亚伦也不公平 对你们大家都不公平
Well,who wants fair?
是吗?谁要公平?
I just want things back,you know, the way they were.
我只想要回失去的，回到往日
- I'm sorry. - Oh,she's sorry. I feel better.
- 我很抱歉 - 她说抱歉，我舒坦多了
I can't believe this!
我真是不敢相信
With the holidays coming up. I wanted him to meet my family.
连续假期就要来临了 我要带他去见我的家人
I'll meet someone. There'll be other Alans.
我会找到新欢的，另一个亚伦
Yeah,right!
是呀,另一个
- Are you guys gonna be okay? - We'll be fine.
- 你们不会有事吧? - 我们会好的
We're just gonna need a little time.
我们只是需要一点时间
I understand.
我了解
- Wow. - I'm really sorry.
- Wow - 我真的很抱歉
Yeah,I mean,I'm sorry too.
我也很抱歉
- But I'm a little relieved. - Relieved?
- 我有点松口气了 - 松了一口气?
Yeah,well,I mean, I had a great time with you.
对，我是说我和你在一起很开心
I just can't stand your friends.
只是我受不了你朋友
Remember when we went to Central Park and rented boats?
记得我们到中央公园划船吗?
That was fun.
没错，那很有趣
He could row like a Viking.
他划得就像维京人一样
So how'd it go?
情况如何?
You know.
你知道的
Did he mention us?
他有提到我们吗?
He says he's really gonna miss you guys.
他说他会想念你们的
- Rough day,huh? - You have no idea.
- 悲惨的一天? - 你无法体会
Come here.
过来宝贝
- That's it. I'm getting cigarettes. - No!
- No! - 我受够了，我要抽烟 - 不行…
I don't care! I'm weak!
我管不了那么多了,我投降,我是懦夫
I've gotta have the smoke!
我要抽烟
If you never smoke again, I'll give you $7000.
如果你不再抽烟我就给你七千块
Yeah,all right.
好吧,没问题